D. Can Ayder

Cambridge, UK 07578 901539 canayder@outlook.com linkedin.com/canayder

Software Engineer

Software engineer experienced in science and engineering domains with focus on microservice architecture, test driven design, domain driven design and object-oriented design. Well-versed in communication and teamwork with different domains. Experience in designing and integration of full stack applications that are highly transactional using .NET Core, ASP.NET Core and Angular frameworks.

KEY SKILLS

Agile Project Delivery Communication

Teamwork Stakeholder Management

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C#, JavaScript/TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Python, R

Technologies / Frameworks: .NET, ASP.NET Core, Object Oriented Design, Domain Driven Design, xUnit Testing, Angular, Jest, Node.js, Express, Asynchronous programming, Multi-Treading, SQL Server, Azure, MongoDB, Microservice, Docker, Kubernetes, Git

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, INSTANDA

Sept 2021 – Current

INSTANDA is a no code, cloud native insurance solution to help carriers and MGAs to create, build insurance products.

Worked within the agile development team on INSANDA web application, to implement new features, improve code quality and test coverage, migrate application from ASP.NET Framework to ASP.NET Core

- Refactored authentication system to allow insurance companies to use their own external authentication system.
- Improved automated test coverage for backend by 20% to increase bug free software delivery.

Software Engineer, University of Edinburgh

Sept 2019 - Sept 2021

The CAMARADES research group aims to address translational failures in preclinical studies using systematic review and meta-analysis.

Worked within the agile development team on Systematic Review Facility (SyRF) web application, to provide one combined tool for systematic review and meta-analysis of data from animal studies.

- Refactored monolithic application to microservices using .NET Core / Docker and implemented messaging system (MassTransit and RabbitMQ) enabling the delivery of new features faster.
- Designed and implemented application frontend on Figma and implemented with Angular Framework, using a test-driven design (TDD) system throughout the ASP.NET Core MVC backend application.

- Wrote unit tests for backend and frontend applications as well as initial end-to-end test for ASP.NET Core application to implement continuous integration/continuous delivery system for faster software update delivery.
- Holding monthly meetings with stakeholders to report status of the application development and ensure that the project delivered on time.

Part of the European Quality in Preclinical Data (EQIPD) consortium funded by the Innovative Medicines Initiative, to standardise available data for analysis performed in work packages.

- Improved the user experience and large file uploading time by refactoring file upload system using asynchronous programming with ASP.NET Framework to process files during upload.
- Held meetings with pharma company representatives and collected feedback and support the implementation of additional functionalities.
- Reorganized and created modules and indexing for SQL Server database for faster data search results
- Managed and validated data prior to upload, identify any errors and updating code or working with users to improve the source data.

Software Engineer, Can Klima Teknik

Dec 2017 – Sep 2019

Company served on air conditioning and ventilation systems, focusing on manufacturing and modelling.

Developed and managed Autodesk Revit Add-In to convert AutoCAD drawings of Air Handling Units to Revit BIM Software.

- Developed the Add-In that uses .NET Framework to allow the Air Conditioning Engineers to quickly and easily convert their technical drawings and work with different suppliers.
- Wrote unit tests (xUnit) and maintained the app to identify any bugs and solve them prior to launch and also for developing further features.
- Worked closely with the Air Conditioning Engineers to identify their requirements and ensure the Add-In met their needs.
- Trained the Engineers on how to use the software.

EDUCATION

VRIJE UNIVERSITEIT BRUSSELS / GHENT UNIVERSITY / UNIVERSITY OF ANTWERP
Joint MSc in Marine & Lacustrine Sci. & Man.

• Thesis: Modelling of Suspended Particulate Material in the Scheldt Estuary (Belgium) Using an Improved One-Dimensional Reactive Transport. Using R and FORTRAN programming languages, an R package was under development as part of this thesis.

ISTANBUL TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY

2010 - 2015

2015 - 2017

BSc in Environmental Engineering

• Thesis: Cumayeri-Gumusova (Duzce, Turkey) Advance Biological Wastewater Treatment Plant Design

SCIENTIFIC PAPERS

Bahor Z, Liao J, Currie G, **Ayder C**, *et al* Development and uptake of an online systematic review platform: the early years of the CAMARADES Systematic Review Facility (SyRF) *BMJ Open Science* 2021;**5**:e100103. doi: 10.1136/bmjos-2020-100103

Currie G, Bahor Z, Liao J, ..., **Ayder C**, *et al* (2019). Living Systematic Review of Alzheimer's Disease Studies, Open Science Framework, doi: https://osf.io/9s8kh/